Lea Ndi Britha Ateh

301 Wile Street, La Porte, IN 46350, leadelve@gmail.com, https://www.linkedin.com/in/lea-ndi-britha-ateh-41b37a111/

Job Objective

Software Engineer / Digital Marketing Specialist / Technical Project Manager (My drive for better communities and inclusion keeps me creative, motivated, and ready to burn the midnight candles)

Qualification Highlights

- Received a community recognition award for leading a community of early and mid-career tech women providing mentorship and coaching that resulted to 3 members winning the Abie award 2022 within a year.
- Co-founded a tech startup that assists companies and organizations align their mission with the digital space to get the best ROI. Leading to a contract of \$221,600 we secured for one of our clients and a total of 15 happy clients in 3 years.

Technical Skills

PM Methodologies: DevOps, Agile, Waterfall and understanding of the SDLC

Infrastructure: Network, database applications, security, storage, servers, and Load balancers

Applications: Adobe photoshop and illustrator, Canvas, Evolus Pencil, Coogle, Visual Paradigm, Figma, WordPress,

Joomla and Drupal. Google and MS Docs, Excel, PowerPoint, Hangouts, Classroom, Trello, Padlet, VS

Code, Notepad, google analytics and more.

Dev tools: PHP, Python, Java, NodeJS, SQL, NoSQL, Bootstrap, Express, Angular, Ionic, Flutter, HTML5, CSS, jQuery,

XML, Vue JS, Ionic, REST/SOAP APIs, GIT, Postman, Heroku.

Work History

Tenshnova(*Co-founder*), Cameroon *Project Manager and Software Engineer*

May 2019 - Present

- Collaborate effectively and consistently with project sponsors, key stakeholders, and team to enlist project support and facilitate the completion of work.
- Cultivate talent, act as coach/mentor, generate momentum while keeping the team focused on deliverables and manage overall project strategy.
- Work with customers to define requirements for product features, data services and solution architecture.
- Developed responsive websites for clients with ecommerce businesses leading to an increase in their sales.
- Collaborated with my team to develop an e-commerce website in 2 weeks, enabling the sale of 90% of the fabric produced during the CSW Artisanal Fair
- Analyzed user needs and software requirements of client projects to determine the feasibility of design, ensuring project completion at least 2 weeks to the due date.
- Contributed to the analysis, design documentation, implementation and testing of a hybrid mobile application used to manage customers and sales.

Paness Conseil, Cameroon Software Developer and Team Lead

Dec 2017 - May 2019

- Participated in sales presentation projects due to my ability to translate user needs into usable software solutions assisting the sales team in closing 4 deals generating over \$120k in revenue.
- Promoted to lead software engineer and team lead due to earning the highest customer satisfaction rate for the software solutions delivered.
- Assisted in documenting all software systems and applications used by the company, effectively training team members and reducing onboarding time by 50%.

• Led a team of over 8 developers in developing an event planning system, taking it from 10% to 85% completion within 3 months less than 60% of the expected time (MEAN STACK).

IT-Kamer, Cameroon

Sep 2015 - Dec 2017

Intern, Junior SW Eng, SW Eng

- Worked with senior engineering teams, assisting with the development of over 9+ software solutions on a wide variety of platforms including mobile, web, and desktop (Java, JS, Bootstrap, and others).
- Contributed to the requirement gathering, analysis, design and testing phase of an ERP SW which reduced the development time by senior developers to 1 month prior to the delivery date.
- Promoted to SW Eng. 11 months ahead of schedule due to strong performance and organizational impact.

Some Volunteer Work

Anitab.org, Cameroon/Special Projects

Sep 2019 - Present

Cameroon Community Lead/Secretary to mentorship committee/Reviewer/Ambassador

• Started the Cameroon community from scratch and built it to over 58 members, and still growing, with over 3 members winning the Abie award 2022.

Leaders For Techy Tomorrow, Cameroon

Sep 2015 - Dec 2018

Founder/President

• An initiative I started in the university, bringing together female engineers from other universities to inspire and support each other through peer mentorship and seminars. With over 30 devoted members and great academic improvements. Two of them own their own start-ups today.

Award and Recognition

- Anitab.org community lead award of recognition at GHC22
- Fully sponsored scholarship for B.Eng. Degree at LMU
- Best Female Student in School and Class Award
- Google Africa developer's scholarship

- Systers PIO award 2022
- VGHC EMEA 2021 scholarship award
- Standford AR bootcamp award
- Best 4 students in class B.Eng. 2015 award

Education

IIE TechWomen Program 2022, San Fransico, California

Feb 2022 – March 2022

Selected as one of 2.6% of 4600 Emerging leaders from the EMEA region for an extensive 5 weeks training program with my host company being Salesforce.

Landmark Metropolitan University College, Buea, Cameroon

Sep 2014 - Nov 2018

Bachelor in Industrial software engineering

Other Professional Trainings, Virtual

Google Africa Developer Scholarship Training – Google Cloud

Cornerstone OnDemand Foundation – Essentials on starting and running a nonprofit organization

Digital Marketing - Google Digital Garage

Developing, Mentoring and Supporting Youth Leadership – Yali Learns

Foundations of User Experience Design - Google (Coursera)

Jul 2020 - Dec 2020

Apr 2020 – May 2020

Present

Aug 2021 – Aug 2021

Aug 2022 - Present

Affiliation

- Anitab.org Mentor, Community Lead, Ambassador, secretory of mentorship committee
- Systers Member

- Women who code Member
- **Yali Network-** Member
- Women in Africa WIA mentor